ruthschris.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy - Ruth's Chris Steak House

This privacy policy, which was updated on May 9, 2016, describes the privacy practices of www.ruthschris.com.  This policy, along with the Terms and Conditions, governs our collection and use of your information, and your choices about this use.

#### Data We Collect

_Information You Provide_

We may collect personally identifiable information directly from you (such as name, address, telephone number, email address, device location, transaction information, credit card information and date of birth), when you:

  * Dine at one of our restaurants, or a restaurant operated by one of our franchisees
  * Make a reservation to dine at one of our restaurants, or a restaurant operated by one of our franchisees 
  * Create an account at www.ruthschris.com
  * Receive a gift certificate
  * Inquire about our services
  * Sign up to receive emails from us
  * Are referred to us through a marketing promotion
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event
  * Pay a deposit in advance of an event or special occasion, such as a wine dinner.

_Information that is collected automatically_

When you visit our website, we will also collect information automatically regarding your use of the website, including the IP address for the computer you are using, device ID, and the pages you visit within our website. 

We may combine the information you provide and the information we collect during your visit to our website with data collected in person at one of our restaurants, or a restaurant operated by one of our franchisees, and with data from other third parties, including publicly available data, in order to better personalize your experience with our website and at our restaurants.

#### Cookies and other technology

This page utilizes cookies, which are small data files stored by your web browser on your computer.  Cookies enable us to enhance and personalize your online experience, and permit us to remember you when you return to our web site, to deliver personalized marketing, and to better understand the way you use our website. 

We may contract with other parties who use cookies or other online tracking tools such as beacons or pixel tags to measure the performance of a marketing effort on our behalf, including email marketing, or to place advertising on our behalf across the internet. 

We may also contract with third party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet.  These advertising companies will use cookies or pixel tags to collect anonymous information about your visits to our website and your interactions with products and services, and may use this information and information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements.  These targeted advertisements may appear on other sites that you visit.  While www.ruthscrhris.com is not designed to recognize a web browser’s “do not track” setting, you may opt-out of receiving this kind of behavioral advertising by clicking here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>. 

You may delete or disable cookies using the settings on your internet browser.  However, our website is optimized to use cookies, so deleting or rejecting cookies may interfere with features of our website or other websites you visit.   

#### How we use the data we collect

We use the data we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with information you have requested
  * To process your reservation requests
  * To provide you with services you have purchased, including gift cards
  * To personalize your experience on our website and our communications with you
  * To improve your experience at our restaurants or at restaurants operated by our franchisees
  * To provide you with relevant and personalized marketing
  * To measure and understand the way you use our website

#### How Data may be shared

We contract with others to provide certain services, including web hosting, online reservation services, email distribution, market research, third party advertising, promotions management, payment processing and fraud prevention and detection services.  These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes.  Some restaurants operating under the Ruth’s Chris brand are operated by franchisees, under an agreement with us.  We may share information with these franchisees in order to facilitate a consistent Ruth’s Chris Steakhouse experience.  If you dine or make a reservation at a Ruth’s Chris Steakhouse operated by a franchisee and sign up to receive emails or if you sign up to receive emails through the email sign up page ([https://www.ruthschris.com/registration](https://www.ruthschris.com/registration/)) and your preferred location is a franchise location, we will provide your email address to the franchisee for that purpose.  Ruth’s Chris franchisees are required by contract to adhere to confidentiality safeguards, and may not use your personal information to promote products or services unrelated to Ruth’s Chris Steakhouses. 

We reserve the right to share information we have collected under this policy with corporate affiliates; in connection with a sale or purchase of business assets; where necessary to protect Ruth’s Chris or Ruth’s Hospitality Group, Inc.; or as required by law.

#### Your Privacy Rights and Choices

If you would like to correct information you have provided to us, including updating your address or telephone number, please contact us at [contact.ruthschris.com](https://contact.ruthschris.com/websurvey/2/execute)

As described above, we may share personal information, such as your name, email address and preferred dining location, with a franchisee operating a restaurant under the Ruth’s Chris brand.  This franchisee may use this information to send you commercial messages and promotions relating to Ruth’s Chris Steakhouses, including emails (if you have signed up for email).  Other than franchisees, we do not share your personal information with any third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  

As described in the section on cookies, you may opt-out of receiving personalized behavioral advertising, including retargeting, by clicking here: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>; 

**

#### Our use of Email

**

You may sign up to receive emails from us by clicking here and providing your email address, or by indicating your desire to be on our email mailing list when making a reservation or when paying for a meal at one of our restaurants.  We use email to confirm your reservation and to follow up regarding your dining experience.   If you have signed up to receive emails from us, we will send you commercial and promotional emails advising you of menu changes, promotions, or other information we believe may be of interest to you.  If you make a reservation at a restaurant operated by a franchisee, and elect to receive emails, or if you sign up to receive emails on our registration form and your preferred location is a franchise location, we will provide your email address to the franchisee, who may send you commercial and promotional emails relating to Ruth’s Chris Steakhouses.  You may choose to stop receiving email promotions and offers from us at any time by following the link provided in each email.   

**

#### Children

**

We do not knowingly collect information about children under 13 years of age.  

**

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

**

We may update this policy in the future.  Please check back for changes to this policy

**

#### Contact Us

**

1030 W. Canton Ave. Suite 100, Winter Park, FL 32789 | [comments@rhgi.com](mailto:comments@rhgi.com) | 407-333-7440
